Starting from the product list, we'll select the "Customizable Desk 80cmW".
On the product form, let's navigate to the "Attributes & Variants" tab.
Here, we can see that the product is configurable by Metal Color, which corresponds to the color of the legs from a different product that will be used.
Next is Size, which describes the Desktop's dimensions. Note that the width and height remain the same for all sizes.
Finally, Thickness values correspond to the various Melamine Board thicknesses.
Now, let's go back and examine a component, the "Metal Legs".
We'll check its "Attributes & Variants" tab as well.
These legs can be customized by width and color, including a custom color option.
Next, we'll return to the list and look at the "Desk Top" component.
Let's open its "Attributes & Variants" to see how it's defined.
This desk top is manufactured from the melamine boards that we will see later and has variants for color, thickness, and various dimensions.
The Desktop Size consists of length and width. Notice that we have values for two different widths, 70 centimeters and 80 centimeters, that will apply to the respective final products.
Let's go back and examine the raw material, the "Melamine Classic board".
On the product form, we can see the unit of measure is set per board, but other units are available.
For example, our custom unit of measure; board with different dimensions, square meters, etc.
Now, let's check the "Attributes & Variants" for this raw material.
The raw board itself has attributes for different colors and thicknesses.
After that, we will proceed to the BoM rules, accessible from the Products menu.